Guide to the Robert Hofstadter Papers SC0426
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2008-003
  - Research
    - EGRET meeting minutes, calibration report, and photographs, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - NASA Proposal, Gamma-Rays, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - NASA, Coded Aperture proposal and correspondence, circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - NASA, X-Ray Astronomy proposal, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - NASA, HEAO correspondence, reports, and clippings, circa 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - NASA, Instrument Development at HEPL for Space Experiments proposal and correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - National Science Foundation, Continuation of HEPL Research proposals, 1975-1976, 1984-1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - SLAC, clippings and technical drawings of new facility, circa 1966 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - High Energy Physics Lab and Microwave Lab, correspondence, budget proposals, and other documents, 1952-1955 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Linear Accelerator Project, HEPL Status Reports, 1953-1959 (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
    - Linear Accelerator Project, HEPL Status Reports, 1959-1964 (Box 15, Folder 16-17)
    - Linear Accelerator Project, HEPL Status Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 18-19)
    - NASA, Spectral Research in X-Ray Astronomy proposal and correspondence, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - PULSAR, research and drafts, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Project M (SLAC) -- Physics Dept (Stanford), circa 1962 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Electron Linear Accelerator (4Bev), proposal, correspondence, and related documents, undated (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
    - HEPL Progress Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Project M (SLAC), circa 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Linear Electron Accelerator status reports (Navy contract), 1951-1952, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Panofsky's Problems," correspondence and reports, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - HEPL Magnet Upgrade, press releases, photographs, and correspondence, circa 1955 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - CERN, notes and data, circa 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - HEPL Modernization Project, New Facilities, correspondence, technical drawings, notes, and related documents, 1964-1969 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Panofsky, notes, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Hansen Labs, Magnets, technical drawings, specifications, and correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Hansen Labs, Magnet (1000 MeV), technical drawings and specifications, 1954-1955 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - SLAC, correspondence, publications, and related documents, 1964-1968 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - SLAC Two-Mile Accelerator, Proposal, Planning and Implementation, circa 1957-1965 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - HEPL Modernization Project, technical drawings, 1962-1966 (Box 16, Folder 16-17)
    - HEPL, Technical Drawings, Targets and Chambers, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - HEPL, Technical Drawings, Spectrometer Details, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - HEPL, Large Spectrometer, budget proposal and correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - HEPL Status Reports, Linear Electron Accelerator Project, 1963-1973 (Box 16, Folder 21-22)
    - Final semester at City College of New York, publications, correspondence, research data, and related documents, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      Honors submission, publications, correspondence, research data, related documents, etc
    - "Microwave Laboratory Survey of Possible Experiments with Linear Electron Accelerators," L.I. Schiff, undated (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - High Energy Electron Scattering by Nuclei (Thesis, Jack Smith, Cornell), 1951 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Rolodex cards with information on contacts, undated (Box 30)
    - Material on discovery of scintilating properties of sodium iodide, circa 1948; Materials were damaged by unknown chemical sometime before arrival at the archives. (Box 36)
  - Research and Writing on Felix Bloch
    Correspondence, clippings, drafts, publications, and other materials related to Hofstadter's colleague and friend Felix Bloch.
    - Obituary, reflections, speeches, and eulogy, circa 1983 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Transcript of taped interview with Bloch, 1968 Aug 15 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, writings, notes, and related documents, 1963-1983 (Box 29, Folder 3-5)
    - "An Introduction to Felix Bloch," International Journal of Modern Physics B, vol. 4 no. 6, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, writings, notes, and related documents, 1963-1983 (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
    - "The Life and Work of Felix Bloch", 1990 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Clippings and publications, 1933-1982 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Bloch talk, notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - "An Introduction to Felix Bloch," Bloch Symposium talk, drafts and notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Bloch manuscript by Hofstadter, draft and notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Bloch Symposium materials, Stanford centennial, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Overhead transparencies, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - German memorials, clippings, and correspondence, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Clippings and publications, 1933-1982 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Speeches and Presentations
    Drafts and final versions of speeches and presentations given by Hofstadter, as well as related correspondence.
    - "Experiment vs. Thought," transcription of interview by Wiktor Osiatynski, circa 1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - SAS-B Gamma Ray Experiment, presentation, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - City College of New York Commencement Speech, drafts, clippings, and related documents, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Israel Bonds" Fund Dinner, speech draft, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Total Absorption Talk and Article, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - San Angelo State College (TX) Commemncement Speech, Foreign Policy, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - University of Toronto and Texas Technical University lectures, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Lepton-Photon Symposium, Tests of Q.E.D lecture, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Science in Action" #487 Script, "High Energy Physics", 1963 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Stanford Physics Graduation speeches, 1979, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "Cross Strands Linking Physics and Medicine," drafts and final copy, circa 1984 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - "Cross Strands Linking Physics and Medicine," notes, data, and illustrations, circa 1983 (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
    - Nuclear Sizes and Density Distribution, Stanford, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - International Conference on Nucleon Structure, Stanford, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Congressional Hearing, Atomic Energy Commmitee, correspondence and agenda, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Robert A. Welch Foundation speech, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Frontiers of Science Lecture, University of Utah, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - High Speed Counters and Use of Crystals of Silver Chloride at Low Temperatures as Counters, Brookhaven Conference Report, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Photoconductivity and Traps, lectures and notes, 1946-1949 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Interpretation of Particle and Nuclear Physics, Lake Louise Conference closing remarks, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Retirement Speech Draft, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - "A Possible Aid to Government Foreign Policy," San Angelo State College commencement speech, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - "The Relation of the Weizmann Institute to Pure Science," speech, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Nobel Lecture, edited manuscript and notes, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - San Angelo State College commencement speech, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Knight Fellowships (Stanford), correspondence with James Risser and related documents, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - CERN Lab Nucleon Talk and Detector Talk, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Loeb Lectureship, Harvard, correspondence and fliers, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - "Thoughts on the Meaning of Modern Science," talk at Federal Judges and Patent Law Association conference, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - German Physical Society speech, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Lecture, event and location unknown, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - "Israel Bonds," speech, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - 11th and 15th Annual Schiff Lecture, introductions, 1982, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - George A. Feigen Memorial Lecture, introductions, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - "Free Spirit in One Free Universe," City College of New York speech, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Lawrence Livermore Lab, presentation material, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Lawrence Livermore Lab, Shiva Facility, Pakistan, presentation, circa 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Travel and Conferences
    Files relating to Hofstadter's travel and conference attendance.
    - "National Conference on Biological Imaging II Clinical Aspect," conference proceedings and ephemera, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Premi Fiuggi, clippings (in Italian) and ceremony program, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Trip to Techinon (Israel), itinerary and correspondence, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Stockholm Trip, correspondence and related documents, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Nuclear Physics and Nuclear Medicine Conference, Clermont-Ferrand, France, circa 1962 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Annual International Conference on High Energy Physics in Kiev, program and clippings, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Annual International Conference on High Energy Physics in Kiev and CERN, correspondence and related documents, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - "Picturesque Wisconsin," Summer Session Outing, itinerary and related documents, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Woods Hole (NASA), National Academy of Sciences, meeting, notes and clippings, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - CERN Conference, correspondence and related documents, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Congres International de Physique Nucleaire, Paris, correspondence and related documents, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - International Conference on Nucleon Structure. proposal, correspondence, and related documents, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Semi-Conductor Nuclear Radiation Detectors and Circuits Conference, Gatlinburg, TN, speech transcript, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Robert A. Welch Conference on Chemical Research, "Nuclear Charge Density Distributions," reprint of address, circa 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - China Invitation, correspondence with Bernard T. Y. Wang, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - 13th Annual SSRL Meeting, correspondence, publications, clippings, and related documents, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - SSRL Users, Synchrotron Angiography Group, proposals, correspondence, publications, and related documents, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Lindau Nobel Gathering (Germany), correspondence, circa 1976 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Nagoya University Trip (Japan), correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - International Conference on Electron Physics, speech, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - CERN Symposium, figures and photographs, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Oberlin College lectures, correspondence and related documents, circa 1971 (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Pakistan Atomic Energy Commission, correspondence, photographs, and related documents, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Marie Curie Anniversary, France, photographs, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Inexhaustible Energy Resources Study, ERDA, conference proceedings and related documents, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Nagoya University, Crystal Ball Experiment, correspondence, notes, and related documents, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Optical Society, correspondence and clippings, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - International Forum on an Acceptable Nuclear Energy Future for the World, University of Miami, correspondence, transcript, and related documents, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - UCLA International Conference on Trends in Astroparticle Physics, program and related documents, circa 1990 (Box 28, Folder 47)
    - Nagoya University, Crystal Ball Experiment presentation, notes and correspondence, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 48)
    - Modern Physics for the Engineer, University of California Tour, program, transcript, and related documents, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 49)
    - Near Zero meeting, correspondence and related documents, 1980-1986 (Box 28, Folder 50)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2011-187
  - Awards and Honors
    Notifications, correspondence, promotional materials, and other documents related to honors and awards received by Hofstadter, including the Nobel Prize.
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, Biography by Leonard Schiff, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - California Academy of Sciences, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Nobel Festival, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Biographical Materials
    Personal correspondence as well as early diary writings.
    - Arizona student interview with Hofstadter for dissertation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Thank you letters to Hofstadter, circa 1961-1986 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Letters of recommendation by Hofstadter, 1947-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, unique characters, circa 1969-1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Diary writings as a teenager (fragile), circa 1931 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence with California State Governor's Office re: Budget Cuts to the State Mental Health Programs, 1967-1976 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence re: California Proposition 15 (Nuclear Shutdown), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence re: Various Political Causes, undated (Box 3, Folder 33-34)
      Includes: peaceful scientists, pugwash movement, Israeli state, world hunger, soviet relations, mental health, draft-deferment, prize nominations, foreign students' rights
    - Correspondence, letter to Gorbachev, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Clippings
    - Clippings and Press, City College of New York honors, Nobel Prize, and other, 1956-1990 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Clippings and Press, various events, circa 1958-1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Press Releases, Stanford, 1957-1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Nobel Prize, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Also includes photographs and correspondence.
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence with "Lin", 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Franz Bumiller, circa 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Bosco Bernardino (Universita di Fiernze, Instituto di Fisica, Italy), 1962-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Robert G. Boeninger, 1962-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: Bloch Festschrift Material, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Ralph Alpher, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Hans A. Bethe, re: Stanford team's scattering findings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, George Gamow, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Don Aiken re: X-Ray Astronomy, etc., 1965-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Luis Alvarez, 1963-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, J.B. Bellicard (Commissariat, A L'Engergie Atomique), re: travel to France and research, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Hans Bienlein (Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron), 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence re: Felix Bloch, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence re: Felix Bloch, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Bronislaw Buras, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence re: Becky Carrington, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence re: "Mr. Chang", Death of, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Ed Condon (National Bureau of Standards), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, Keith Edwards, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Memorial Tribute to Bill Ewings, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, George Feigen, 1964-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, Carl Fichtel re: EGRET, etc, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, Gerald A. Fisher re: EGRET, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, Colleagues and Friends, various, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence re: Jerome Friedman, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, Henry J. Gomberg, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, Cecil Green, re: American Academy of Achievement, etc, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence re: P.C. Gugelot, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, Joseph E. Henderson, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, W.E. Van Heyninger, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, Richard Hofstadter (historian, distant relative of Robert Hofstadter), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, Al M. Hudson, 1955-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence re: E. Barrie Hughes, 1960-1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence re: Borris Jacobsohn, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence re: Inga Karliner, 1969-1989 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, Henry Kendall, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence re: G.I. Kirkbride, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, Boran Leontic, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, Arthur Levenson, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, John A. McIntyre, 1957-1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, Bettie McKeeman, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, Ulrich Meyer - Berkhout, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence re: Pete Michelson, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence, Lloyd Motz, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, Margaret J. Rabbinowitz, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, Leonidas K. Resvanis, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, Ed Rubenstien, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence re: Arthur Schalow, Nomination for National Medal of Science, 1966-1990 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence re: Lee and Ellen Schiff, circa 1949-1977 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence re: L.I. Schiff, 1949-1977 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence, Melvin Schwartz, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence, Jing Shen, 1981-1987 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, Max Shiffman, 1956-1975 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, E.J. Sternglass, 1956-1969 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, Karl Strauch, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence, John F. Streib (University of Washington), 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, Larry R. Suelzle, 1956-1966 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence, Wesley J. Van Sciver, 1953-1968 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence, Claudio Villa, 1958-1965 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence, Conrad de Vries (Physics Institute of Amsterdam), 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence, Bernard Wang, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence, Eugene P. Wingor, 1961-1977 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Correspondence, Richard Wilson, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, Jerome Fregeau, National Science Foundation, Draft Proposal, circa 1967 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence, Alexander Abashian, National Science Foundation, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence re: National Science Foundation Fellowship, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence re: National Science Foundation Grant and Usage, 1961-1988 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Correspondence re: Research Corporation (Santa Monica, CA), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Correspondence, Letters of Commendation and Replies, 1956-1984 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Correspondence, Guinness Book of World Records, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Correspondence re: Faber Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Correspondence, Scientific American, 1955-1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Daniel Gladstone (Physics Today), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re: Book Edited by Hofstadter and Leonard Schiff, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, Institutional, 1958-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, University of California, Berkeley, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: Employment Matters, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re: John Fluke, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re: KMS Fusion, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Soviet Scientists, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, University of Wyoming, Archives of Contemporary History, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence re: National Conference on Biological Imaging Participation, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence re: Electron Scattering, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence re: Weizmann Institute of Science, 1963-1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Technion (Israel), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence re: Scintillation Counters History and H. Kallmann, 1966-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence re: Congres International de Physique Nucleaire et de Medicine Nucleaire, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence re: Inaugural Ball Invitation, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence re: Early SLAC History and "Project M", 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Includes technical drawings, photographs, related documents, meeting minutes, etc.
    - Correspondence, Pief Panofsky re: Disagreements on SLAC Matters, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence re: Disagreement with Dean Heffner and SLAC People, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence re: Acknowledgement (Credit -- SLAC vs. Hofstadter), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, Pief Panofsky re: Relationship between Physics Department and SLAC, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence re: Attempt for Run Time at SLAC, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence re: SLAC Problems (General), 1954-1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, Leonard Schiff re: Physicists at SLAC and "Project M", 1956-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence re: Obituary for Mark Zemansky (CCNY), 1961-1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, Robert Marshak (CCNY), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence re: CCNY Commencement Address, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence re: CCNY, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence re: Atomic Accelerator Idea, 1967-1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence re: Voting Suggestion, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence re: Stanford Village Housing, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence re: Department of Physics, undated (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
    - Correspondence re: Gunmount, Spectrometers, etc, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence re: High Energy Physics Lab (HEPL) Matters, 1958-1963, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence re: High Energy Physics Lab (HEPL) Dispute, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, Stanford Colleagues, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence re: Steel Fund, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
    - Correspondence re: Graduate Student Matters, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence re: Principal Investigator after Retirement, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence, Dirk Walecka, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence re: Honors/Awards, Nominations, circa 1963-1990 (Box 2, Folder 46-48)
    - Correspondence, Henry Semat (CCNY), 1961-1975 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence re: Retirement Celebration, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence re: California Museum of Science and Industry Awards, 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence, Nobel Prize Matters, 1961-1980 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence re: Nobel Hall of Science (MN), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence re: Lindau Meeting, 1962, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, G.K. O'Neill, circa 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, NASA and Berkeley, Gamma Rays, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, GRO/EGRET, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)